The ancient Chinese pictograms for reveal and man and garden make up the character for God.
Thus we see God's purpose is to reveal himself to the man whom he formed and
placed in the garden
combining the pictograms for God and one and man and garden fawns the character for
Happiness or blessing God set up a special relationship with the man Adam to bring happiness and blessing
combining the pictograms for two trees and
command forms the character for the word forbidden
this provides a summary of the conditions of the edenic Covenant.
How extraordinary that the Chinese pictograms for two trees and
command should be used to compose the word forbidden.
There is no logic in this apart from the Bible narrative in Genesis.
The ancient Chinese pictograms for life of motion and secret or
private and garden
and man form the character for devil or Satan.
This is an appropriate description.
In of how Satan entered into the garden by stealth and subtlety.
The pictograms for cover and two trees and devil form the character for tempter
an accurate description of what Satan did in the garden by tempting Eve?
The pictograms for man and
fruit form a character naked having Patinkin.
Of the two didn't fruit Adam and
Eve realized their nakedness before God.
The pictograms for ancient and
weeds form the character sorrow
thorns and thistles would come up instead of productive fruit
man's Disobedience to God's command brought sorrow into the world.