In part 1 We Looked at The Logical version of the problem of suffering and evil
this argument attempt to show that since suffering and evil exist.
It is logically impossible for God to exist and
we explained why even atheist philosophers admit that this argument fails
But wait,
it may still be argued that while it's logically possible that God and suffering.
Both exist is far from likely
there's just so much pointless suffering. It seems improbable that God could have good reasons for permitting it.
This is the probability version of the problem
suffering provides empirical evidence that God's existence is not impossible. Just highly unlikely. Is this a good argument
Consider three points
first, we are not in a position to say with any confidence
that God probably lacks reasons for allowing the suffering in the world.
The problem is that we're Limited in space and time and in intelligence and insight
God on the other hand sees every detail of history from beginning to end
and orders it through people's free decisions and actions
in order to achieve his purposes God.
Have to allow a great deal of suffering along the way
suffering which appears pointless within our limited scope of understanding
may be seen to have been justly permitted by God within his wider framework.
Sometimes what we experience makes no sense until
we gain a wider perspective and
see the big picture designed by the Creator.
Here's the second Point relative to the full scope of the evidence God's existence May.
Well be probable you see probabilities are always relative to background information. For example,
if we consider only how much this man ways we would say is highly improbable that he's a world-class athlete,
but when we're willing to consider new information that he's a professional sumo wrestler and
World Champion we quickly
Is our view in the same way when the atheist claims that God's existence is improbable.
We should ask improbable relative to what background information
if we consider only the suffering in the world. Then God's existence may very well appear to be improbable.
But if we're willing to look at the full scope of background information
to take into account the powerful Arguments for God's existence.
We may come to a very different conclusion.
The third point is Christianity and Tails doctrines that increase the probability of the coexistence of God and suffering
consider four of these first. The chief purpose of life is not happiness people often assume that if
God exists his role is to create a comfortable environment for his human pets.
They think the ultimate goal of Our Lives on Earth is happiness.
And therefore God is obligated to keep us happy.
However, Christianity presents a radically different view
that the purpose of life is to know God this alone brings true lasting fulfillment
suffering can bring about a deeper more intimate knowledge of God,
even the part of the one who is suffering or those
Found him
the whole point of human history is that God
having given us Freewill is drawing as many people as he can into his unending Kingdom
suffering is one of the ways God can draw people freely to himself.
In fact countries that have endured the most hardship often show the highest growth rates for Christianity.
God Whispers to us in our Pleasures speaks in our consciences but
shouts in our pains
it is his megaphone to Rouse a deaf world.
Second mankind is in a state of rebellion against God and
his purpose terrible.
Human Evils are testimony to man's depravity a consequence of his alienation from God.
The Christian isn't surprised that moral evil in the world on the contrary. He expects it
the third Doctrine states that God's purpose
is not restricted to this life but
spills over beyond the grave into eternal life.
This world is just the beginning the entryway to an unimaginable never-ending life beyond death store
Paul who wrote much of the New Testament underwent afflictions hardships calamities beatings imprisonments hunger
yet.
He wrote
We do not lose heart
for this slight momentary Affliction is preparing us for an eternal weight of Glory beyond all comparison
because
Look not to the things that are seen But to the things that are unseen
for the things that are seen are transient,
but the things that are unseen
are Eternal
Paul understood that life on Earth and
whatever suffering it holds for each of us is temporary.
Our pain will not endure forever,
but our lives with God will
Paul was not belittle in the plight of those who suffer horribly in this life indeed he was
None of them,
but he saw that those suffering
will be overwhelmed Forever by the ocean of joy that God will give to those will freely receive it.
And the fourth Doctrine is this the knowledge of God is an incomparable good
knowing god is the ultimate fulfillment of human existence an infinite good.
Thus the person who knows God no matter how much he has suffered can still say
God is good to me.
So if Christianity is true,
it's not at all improbable that suffering and
evil should exist.
In summary for all these reasons the probability version of the problem of evil is no more successful than the logical version as a purely intellectual problem.
Then the problem of evil does not disprove God's existence. But even if those intellectual arguments fail the emotional problem of suffering and
evil remains very powerful if you have suffered deeply or
if you've watched someone
Love go through intense pain.
You may be thinking
so what if God exists,
why would I want to respond to him or worshipping
I feel cold and
empty. I want nothing to do with him.
You're not alone.
God knows your name. He knows who you are and
what you're going through
God promises to be with you through your suffering. He can give you the strength to endure.
Jesus Christ also suffered,
although he was innocent.
He was tortured and
sentenced to death
his suffering had a purpose to provide you and
me with a life-giving connection to God
not only does God exist,
but he loves you. He seeks after you
he offers you hope.
And in time you will make all things new he will wipe every tear from their eyes.
There will be no more death or Mourning or crying or pain
for the old Order of Things has passed away.