I'm a synthetic organic chemist
origin of life is purely synthetic organic chemistry.
There's no way around it.
I'm perfectly situated to be commenting on
this to be critiquing the origin of Life research.
It is a biological it is before biology takes over.
This is purely synthetic organic chemistry.
Some people argue that
since there's been hundreds of millions of years of vailable
the probability that there's the chance that
these things could happen in hundreds of millions of years,
but that's not true time actually can be an enemy
when it comes to organic synthesis Prebiotic synthesis is before biology.
So one has to make chemicals
many of the chemicals that need to be made for life.
Our kinetic products meaning that
they're not the most thermodynamically stable form for example carbohydrates,
which is the main class of compounds.
This is the these are the the units that hook together DNA.
These are the units that I have identifying aspects on cell structure.
These are the units that the cell is going to need for.
The energy of Life carbohydrates are kinetic products
meaning that if they should form they would decompose.
Decompose over time and relatively short amounts of time.
They decompose the very reactions that
make them unless somebody is there to pull them out to
fish them out to stop the process and
put them in a bottle under anaerobic conditions
in a freezer and not just one.
There's many many different types you have to do this
they end up going through a process of
what's referred to as caramelization.
Meaning that they polymerize they polymerize the very real
All reactions that were used to make them just continue
and you get poly Aldo's you get poly condensation reactions and
they caramelize or they undergo with formaldehyde
which is a presumed Prebiotic chemical.
They undergo rapid cannizzaro reactions.
So the aldehyde is oxidized to formic acid and
this nice carbohydrate that you made has just been reduced.
So the so the aldehyde the from the carbohydrate is gone back to an alcohol.
So there's competing reactions.
Shins so time does not solve the issue.
The other problem is if you had 400 million years
to get to a certain point in
a synthesis of a particular class of compounds now,
you run out of material.
Anytime you do synthesis, you run out of material,
even when you've optimized deals and
you got to go back to the beginning.
Well say it took you four hundred million years
to get to a certain point on a synthesis.
Now, you have to go back and make more
but how do you go back and make more
because nature never kept a laboratory.
Notebook never doesn't doesn't know
how to go back never kept the record.
So even if it could make more
it doesn't know how to
so it's got to start all over again
some but it doesn't know how to start over again.
When doesn't know why they start over again
because it's doesn't know what it's going toward.