What is your answer to the absence of free will
if God created every fiber of our being every atom every impulse Duty not also creates in
did he not also create Satan and his actions?
Let me go first and
then Vince will give you the substance of it.
I'll take a stab at that.
If the question is to hold together every assumption that is in that
what is the purpose of God doing that then? Of course,
I'm assuming you also are
wanting God to remain in the Paradigm
and that he is the creator of the universe and your life and mine.
When you know that an infinite perfect,
God has created you and me.
There are only four possibilities of God and
creation. Number one that God would create nothing
nothing at all.
Number two where he would create a world where there was no such thing as good or evil,
uh name or
world number three where he would create a world where we
Only choose good
or number four
create this world where there's the possibility of Good and
Evil with the freedom given to us.
No creation
a moral world
where we would only choose good or
create a world like this where he has given us the freedom to choose good
and evil,
this is the only one of the four worlds in which Love Is Possible.
If love is the Supreme ethic
and love is the ethic towards rich on the longing towards which we all stryer.
This is the only one of the four possibilities
in which love is given to us as a legitimate possibility
that me give you
the illustration from a child and
then move into some philosophical extensions of that.
You know,
when you are a parent
you look at life very differently than before you raise your first child.
Then when you are a grandparent you look at it even more differently
than you did when you were a parent when you're a parent you are so preoccupied with the worries and the fears
and that your time is given over
to that stress dissonance
when you've got grandkids the wonderful thing is somebody else does the worrying
and you can just hug and hold and Say Goodbye at the end of the day
and get your life back again and get your house back again.
I don't know why a country musician is not yet written a song about this.
Soon as they go you get your house back you get your toys back you get everything back.
But I watched my grandkids
GK Chesterton said he learned more from observing children than he ever did from going studying philosophy
my three and
a half year old grandson Jude who is now 6,
he's a guy with an amazing vocabulary.
I don't know where he gets it from but
he's got it.
He's the guy who dangles us feet at the table and
looks across the table and
says to you papa
what he six now Surah he was about five and
he looked at me and
he said Papa.
What is the meaning of sophomoric?
Who's
teaching this guy? Where is he getting all of this? Right?
So nice three now is a wee little tyke sweet little boy precious little guy
and his mother had lost her car keys,
and she's looking all over the place and confounded.
She pauses her daughter Naomi stops her forehead and says,
I must be losing my mind.
Jude comes and
stands in front of her and
said Mommy whatever you do,
please don't ever lose your heart because I'm in there.
Tell me.
Where does he come up with something like that
the longing to look at his mother and
say to her don't ever lose your heart.
I'm in there
love is the craving of the human heart
to belong in the sacredness of trust and a relationship
and that is what you longed for. And I longed for
God and giving us freedom gave us the greatest possible gift we could ever have with the Great.
Possible vulnerability
at the same time
and once you know him
and follow him and love him and enjoy his love
you will realize that for the sake of love and
for the sake of that relationship with you.
He gives gives you that freedom
and there are only two kinds of Destinies that you have
you can bend your knee to God said serious Lewis
and say to him your will be done
or you refuse to bend that knee.
Need to him and
he says to you your will be done.
If you really watched wish to enjoy the freedom
of what this gift is all about for creativity and all
then this is the world that gives you the possibility
of love and
the beauty of the sacredness of a relationship the more you get to know him
the less you ask the other question because you know in his wisdom he has an explanation that
In time and in eternity
will be ultimately revealed that me give you one illustration and
turn it over to Vince.
You take your two year old to a doctor
for an injection
and the doctor is about to jab that needle and the two-year-old start screaming and sits at the back of the car. And on the way back says
I don't understand my mother
she brought me here
for him to Jap this in my arm.
Not only that I saw her paying him for doing that to me.
And then comes a few years that go by and
as a disease stalking the land
and that little one has grown up and said if my mother hadn't done that
I would be a victim for what exactly is blinking the country.
Now
time is a necessary component for understanding the big picture.
I have no doubt. God gives us the big picture when we say
I know get it. That is my brief. Answer to thank you.
Well one way to understand this challenge is that God is all good and
God only creates good things.
So how is it that putting good things together if that's all that God creates could wind up with sin and evil.
Let me just quickly give you
a more trivial example,
but one that I find helpful
in understanding this and
then a more serious illustration from my life
the example that I find helpful is going to a buffet anyone like going to a buffet
I really like going to a buffet but
I am not a good Buffet eater
because I go to the buffet and
everything individually looks great.
And I'm not able to process the fact that some of these things don't go well together.
And so I put all of them on my plate
and it doesn't go. Well then or
for the rest of the night.
That's how I think about this God only creates good things,
right? He creates the power for me to move my arm.
He creates the power for me to have free will
they're both good things. I can use my arm to help someone up.
But if I put those two things together in the wrong way,
then it's not a good thing.
And the more serious illustration in my life that makes me reflect deeper on this
is of someone who has a child.
I can remember as a teenager. I wasn't very kind to him and
he wasn't very kind to me
and I use those powers that God gave me to push him down rather than to help him up.
And I remember taking every opportunity I could to put this guy down
and then I learned a number of years ago that he had taken his life.
And at one point the Bible says for the wages of sin is death and
I had read that verse hundreds of times and
it never really hit me until then and
I had to start asking questions.
Like would he have taken his life had I been kind to him had I use those very same powers of the movement of my arm and of the free will not to push him down but
to help him up and I didn't know the answer to those questions. Sometimes I think we're too quick to look up and blame.
God for the evil in the world and
we're too slow
to look to ourselves and turn that question around and ask.
What is our part
in that GK Chesterton was once asked to write into a newspaper with an answer to the question what's wrong with the world and
he wrote a very short letter. He wrote dear sirs.
I am sincerely yours GK Chesterton.
And so sometimes I think we're too quick to look up and blame God
ironically the same God who when he was hanging down.
Across
looked at the ones who are producing evil in his life and
the instinctive words of his heart or father
forgive them.