Evidence is a hugely important thing
and we need to clear up a total misunderstanding.
And that is that say my Christian faith
is not evidence based faith is believing where you know,
there's no evidence.
That is utter nonsense.
Why do I believe it because
I believe there's powerful evidence.
If you ask the basic document of the Christian faith
what it means by faith if will tell you directly and
let me give you a quotation of the purpose of
the Gospel of John the Fourth gospel.
It says this many other signs Jesus did
in the presence of his disciples
which are not written in this book,
but these are written that
You might believe that Jesus is the Messiah
the Son of God and that believing
you might have life in his name.
In other words, John is saying these things that
I've collected and written down they are to
form the basis of belief
that is there evidence.
Now, of course you want to know at what level
or evidence and we could go all night talking about that.
But the crucial thing to perceive is
when Christianity was launched on the world.
World it was launched On The World by people.
From a very unexpected background a Jewish background
who started to say that they had evidence of meeting Jesus Christ
risen from the dead.
So my Christian faith is based on evidence.