We are here to talk about big questions.
Maybe the biggest question of all
does God exist.
I won't give you a proof tonight.
But I hope I will give you some things to think about
things that have led me from being an atheist
to becoming a Believer and
a follower of Jesus.
Perhaps the most widespread fundamental assumption
in the intellectual West today is that
there is no reality beyond what natural science discovers
and that there is no Authority or good higher than the
Freedom of the individual now
both science and individual Freedom are good,
but followers of Jesus like me have a different view.
We believe that both the deepest reality and
the highest moral meaning or good authority
are to be found in loving relationship.
Why is nature regular?
Why does it follow regular laws that
even like can we understand them
and we're so used to these ideas today that
we don't realize that there weren't actually that obvious to most people through
Most time and the reason for that is if you just live.