And the one hand academic work and research contributes to Faith
but on the other I think my Christian beliefs
provide an overarching framework of understanding
of trying to discern how Knowledge
from different disciplines fit together.
And what does it all mean?
And I started reading the Bible and
to my not wanting to tell anybody what was happening in me.
I started to change it started to change me and
I thought it would be sort of full of Fantastical crazy stuff.
They actually had me start with Proverbs
which was smart because it was full of so much wisdom that
I'd read a few verses and I have to put it down
and Ponder what was going on here and
it immediately hit me with
my you know,
my sort of intellectual arrogance
that I had a lot to learn from what was written here.
After a period of consideration,
I did reach the point of realizing that
I kind of did believe this that Christianity made sense to me
made intellectual sense to me and that I needed to
if I were to be true to what I thought was reality
and what I now think is reality that
I needed to take a step of commitment
and faith and and become a follower of Jesus
and that and that's I did that and
I was baptized as on my 20th.
birthday actually in the chapel of King's College, Cambridge
And I'm studying issues of culture and race in my work
and you know, not quite audibly
but audibly and understandably God just kind of said
hey, you know, I'm bigger than your African-American Miss.
I'm bigger than your racial background.
In fact, I created racial and ethnic identity
and different cultures.
I created at your study at let me show it to you.
For more information about the Veritas Forum
including additional recordings and a calendar of upcoming events.
Please visit our website at Veritas dot-org.