Isn't Christianity at its core the same as other religions,
if you could put it in a pot and
boil it down wouldn't the remainder smell look and
taste the same as Judaism Islam Buddhism
Hinduism. And the rest
what is religion
just as we refer to our minds is being thoughts and
ideas beyond the electrical impulses of our physical brain,
the major religions proposed that
the humans true Essence is their soul instead of their physical body,
but just like our physical bodies the soul also
so has needs or
it will starve
each religion proposes to be a guidebook of that spiritual plane that helps lead are starving souls to sole bread
aren't these guidebooks all the same
the historical Jesus of Nazareth told a story about a father two sons and
a family business.
It was custom that
the sons would split the business when their father died,
but the younger son said to his father.
I can't wait for you to die.
Give me my money now
seeing his sons True Heart the father gave it up to him the sun turned his back.
His family and hit the road
far away.
He party like an animal eating and drinking and paying prostitutes until suddenly his pockets were empty
in desperation.
He found a job feeding pigs,
but the country's economy crashed and
he couldn't even make enough to feed himself
now broke and starving.
He found himself craving the pig slop
when it suddenly hit him that
there was probably food back home.
What do you think should this father let him back into the house
as long as the sun works hard to pay his father back.
Then he should be able to get a place for the family table again.
Right?
Let's see how Jesus ended the story
The Son decided to return admit his wrong and
asked his father for a minimum wage job,
but still a ways from home
his father spotted him and
ran out to him and
wrapped him in a bear hug
remorseful the sun began his plea dad.
You shouldn't even call me your son anymore,
but the
Put a fine robe on him and
a ring with a family crest.
He told his workers
get the best meat and
prepare a welcome home Feast for this son of mine was dead
and has come to life again.
He was lost and
has been found.
Although Jesus told this as a story
he was actually presenting his view of the truth in the story The Father represents God
so is Jesus seriously teaching that
God forgives selfish gluttons before they repaid their wrongs against him and others
Judaism teaches that one can atone for their wrongs by changing their behavior praying and
doing good deeds
Islam says we can move towards Paradise by performing The Five Pillars.
Hinduism claims that if we store up enough Good Karma will reunite with Brahman
Buddhism says we can Enlighten and
discipline ourselves into Nirvana by practicing the Eightfold Path.
But in this story The Father embraced his son and
fed him before he did any work why
because in Jesus is view.
It's impossible for a person to repay God for their bad Deeds.
God is a perfect judge who cannot be bought off with anything that
we have to offer.
Jesus said that when we die
We will face God with all of our Deeds laid out.
None of us is completely morally perfect and
none of us will stand a chance of justifying ourselves.
Then is there hope for us Jesus believe so and
staked his life on it.
He claimed to be God in human form who came to pay our moral debt with his innocent life
so that if anyone truly believed and
surrendered to him,
they would receive a full pardon from God and
the power to change how they live
other religions teach that
our own self sacrifice can pay our
Our debt but Jesus taught that
only God's own self sacrifice can pay our debt.
All other religious Founders claim to be guides to lead are starving souls to bread.
Jesus claimed to be the bread our soul star for