In ad 203 the Roman government arrested a 22 year old woman a Christian named perpetua.
The problem wasn't so much that
she worshipped Jesus her crime was that
she worshipped only Jesus
she refused to worship any other gods.
As a result,
she was found guilty of treason and
sentenced to death
this dangerous idea that
Christ Alone provides.
The way to God
is called Christian particularism and
it is a scandalous today as it was 2000 years ago
religious pluralism on the other hand
is the view that
all the world's religions are equally valid and
Christ is just one of many ways.
Some religious pluralist say all the world's religions teach basically the same thing so they are all true.
But this is clearly mistaken
the major religions often contradict each other.
For example,
compare Islam and Buddhism
Muslims believe there is a personal God who created the world
man is sinful and
will spend eternity in heaven or hell
and salvation is attained by faith and
Performing good work.
X
but Buddhist deny all of this.
They believe that Ultimate Reality is not a person the world was not created man is not sinful
man is not an enduring self.
And the goal of life is not salvation.
It's anihilation
because these two worldviews contradict each other.
They can't both be true.
In fact,
every major world religion contradicts every other one so they can't possibly all be true.
So other religious pluralist swill say
all the world's religions are false.
They're equally valid but
equally false cultural expressions of Mankind's search for truth.
But why I think that
this is true why couldn't one particular religion be true
when you examine the arguments for religious pluralism,
you find that some of them are textbook examples of logical fallacies, for example,
anyone who believes that Christianity is
is true and every other view is wrong is arrogant therefore Christianity is false.
This is a logical fallacy called argument ad hominem
trying to show someone's view is false by attacking his personal character.
This is a logical fallacy because
the truth of a view
is independent of the character of the person who holds it
for example,
if an arrogant person discovered the cure for cancer the fact that he's egotistical.
Would not mean his claim was false
and you wouldn't refuse treatment just because
he was conceited
moreover.
This objection is a double-edged sword for the pluralist also believes that
his view is true
and that everyone else is wrong.
Therefore
if you're arrogant for holding to a view which many others disagree with
then the pluralist himself would be guilty of arrogance.
Here is another pluralist argument religions are
Culturally relative
if you had been born in Pakistan,
you'd likely be a Muslim.
But if you've been born in Ireland,
you'd probably be a Catholic
because religious beliefs are culturally relative.
They are not objectively true.
This is an example of the genetic fallacy
trying to invalidate a view by showing how a person came to hold the view.
This is a fallacy because
the truth of a view is independent of how a person came to believe it
for example,
If you had been born in ancient Greece you would have believed that
the Sun goes around the earth.
Does that make your current belief that the earth goes around the Sun false or unjustified know
furthermore.
This objection is also a double-edged sword
for if the religious pluralist had been born in Pakistan or Island.
He'd likely have been a religious particular has
so he's belief in religious pluralism is just the result of his being born in contemporary ways.
Stand society and therefore is not objectively true.