Appreciate that question and
it's a question that
has the assumption that
is very correct
often times.
The Christian takes the hit
that he or she was a follower of Jesus Christ is the only one who lays claim to exclusivity that
is not true.
Got them a Buddha was born a Hindu
and here announced two of the fundamental doctrines of Hinduism
the authority of The Vedas
and the caste system.
He could not accept those two
went on his own journey in search of Enlightenment and
came off course with the
Four noble truths and
the Eightfold Path
and the ultimate extinguishing of desire
in this nirvanic Pursuit.
So he turned his
belief away from the religion of his birth in order to find a different answer
Islam is also exclusive aesthetic in its claim
in all of its precepts and it's five pillars and so on.
What about these contradistinction 's
The first thing we need to know is
there are distinctions.
There are fundamental differences at best.
There are superficial similarities.
I often hear the question posed wrongly
they'll say are all really aren't all religions fundamentally the same and
superficially different know
they are fundamentally different and
at best they are superficially similar.
What are the fundamental claims for example in Buddhism.
The goal is to escape extinguish.
GE extinguish desire.
I remember talking to the first woman monk
who is from Thailand to be ordained into the Buddhist.
Priest Hood,
but Thai Buddhist do not ordain
women. So she went to Sri Lanka
to be ordained and
she has a PHD in Philosophy from McMaster University in Hamilton,
Ontario and
Waterloo, I guess Ontario and
McMaster devere University there
got her PhD in philosophy and
she gave me the first
View we chatted for well over an hour one on one
and I sort of angled into some questions because
I didn't want to be too discourteous.
And one of the things I said to her is I hear you're married and
she said yes
I said you have children.
She said yes
I said but you're living in a temple by yourself.
She said yes.
I said you not see your children.
She started crying.
She said I have a car
I said you have a car she said yeah,
she said okay,
so she
drove herself because she can't allow a man to drive her.
She said so she has to drive herself
and she says every evening at the end of the day.
I try and meet up with one of my children.
She said this is the hardest part of my life
I said so you are on the journey to extinguishing the desire to be with your children.
Is that right? Is that a fair assessment?
She kept quiet.
And then I said this I said the Dalai Lama
has as as primary Pursuit now
the freedom of Tibet she said that's right.
I said,
why does he desire that?
She looked at me and
she said we try not to get into these philosophical questions.
Let's just say that
he chooses to
you take a look at other world religions
and see where these four questions are dealt with origin meaning morality and Destiny.
These four questions have to be answered in two ways.
Follow me, please
every particular answer has to correspond to truth
either through empirical form of measurement or
through the logical reasoning process
and windows for answers are put together.
They must go here.
And not be incoherent so the to test correspondence and coherence.
I guarantee you only in the judeo-christian worldview.
Will you find these four questions answered with corresponding truthfulness
and with the coherence of a world view? Let me take just one example,
and I don't say this to slight but
this is a fact and
we have to deal with it.
I've been invited in many many Islamic countries and
I have open forums there and
going to go to one of the toughest Islamic countries with the next few weeks.
They've hosted me in many parts there and
we've had dialogues.
I want to give to you two things.
in the Quran
it is the only historical Lee claimed document
that denies that Jesus Christ was actually crucified or
died on the cross denies that
the Greek historians say he died on the cross Roman historians.
Say that
Pagan historians say that Jewish historians say that and
Christian historians say that
the Islamic
the the Quran is the only one that says it appeared to him that he died,
but he didn't actually die on the cross.
So historically it is making a formation
that is really historically untrue.
I got into a discussion with Sheikh Hussein of the leading.
Shiite cleric in Damascus Syria as a real gentleman
for over three hours.
We talked with an interpreter between us
and an audience listening and
I was allowed to ask him one question about his faith and
he was allowed to ask me one question.
But mine
there was nothing no Rancor no adversarial stance just a perspective encounter perspective and back and forth
It's the best way to do it really
at the end of it Sheikh husam looked at me was very respectful to the whole time always refer to me as professor.
Zachary has Professor Zacharias
and then at the end he looked at me leaned over and he said,
you know professor.
I think the time has come
for us in the Islamic world to stop asking if Jesus Christ died and
to start asking why.
I said to him.
May I quote you on that sir?
He said yes,
you may I'm am hopefully going to go there before long and
I hope we can meet up again
origin meaning morality and Destiny
the judeo Christian worldview is not the only one that claims exclusivity
but is the only one that takes those four questions with corresponding answers that are truthful
and coherent answers that
stand the test of time
and the ultimate answer of the Resurrection from the dead
that gives you hope and
meaning I see we have one more
more question left and
that's the sign here.
I'll be happy to take that.