Evolution you learned about it in high school.
It goes like this life started out
with very simple forms and then
gradually over hundreds of millions of years
morphed into all the forms.
We see today bacteria to Beethoven not a straight line,
of course, but that's roughly how it went.
This was the theory proposed by Charles Darwin in 1859
and with some modification.
It's been embraced as unassailable
by the scientific community over the last century.
As evolutionary biologist Richard Dawkins says
if you meet somebody
who claims not to believe in evolution
that person is either ignorant stupid or insane.
But is that right
are there no, scientific reasons to doubt
The evolutionary count of life's origins in November 2016.
I attended a conference in London convened
by some of the world's leading evolutionary biologists
the purpose to address growing doubts about
the modern version of Darwin's theory.
Let's look at just two scientific reasons to doubt this Theory
first the Cambrian explosion a weird
and wonderful thing happened 530 million years ago a whole
each of major groups of animals
what scientists call the phyla
appeared abruptly within a geologically short window of time
about 10 million years
these novel animal forms exhibiting
prototypes of most animal body designs.
We see today emerged in the fossil record
without evidence of earlier ancestors.
Did you catch that
a huge number of diverse animals
appeared with no discernible antecedents?
So where do they come from
this question really bothered Darwin
and he acknowledged that
he could give it no satisfactory answer
nor can scientists today.
The renowned biologist Eugene. Koonin
of the national Center for biotechnology information
describes the abrupt appearance of the Cambrian animals
and other organisms such as dinosaurs birds flowering plants and mammals
as a pattern of biological Big Bangs.
So what caused all these new forms of life to arise
That question leads to a second big doubt
the DNA Enigma in the 1950s James Watson and Francis Crick
made a startling Discovery the DNA molecule stores information
as a four-character digital code strings
of precisely sequence chemicals
inside the DNA Helix store,
the instructions the information for building the crucial proteins
that cells need to survive
unless the chemical letters in the DNA texts are sequenced properly.
A protein molecule will not form no proteins.
No cells. No cells. No living organisms.
Bill Gates has said DNA is like a software program.
Let's think about that for a second
for computers to run faster and perform more functions.
They require new code.
Well, the same is true for life to build new forms of life.
The evolutionary process would need to
produce new genetic information new code.
But this raises questions about the creative power
of natural selection of mutation
natural selection is a simple sorting process
species keep favorable mutations that allow them to survive.
I've but eliminate bad mutations that cause their members to die out.
No one doubts that natural selection is a real process
and that it produces minor variations,
but many biologists now doubt that it produces major Innovations in biological form
to see why I think again about software
what happens if you introduce a few random changes into computer code,
you'll likely mess it up right though.
It might still work if you don't make too many changes,
but if you make
enough random changes your program
will stop functioning all together.
You certainly can't keep doing this and expect some cool new program to pop out.
There's a mathematical reason for this in all codes and languages.
There are vastly more ways of arranging characters that will generate gibberish.
Then there are Arrangements that will generate meaningful sequences
and this applies to DNA remember natural selection
only selects sequences that random mutations generate.
Yet experiments have established that
DNA sequences capable of making stable proteins are extremely rare
and thus really hard to stumble on randomly.
How rare
while working at Cambridge University molecular biologist Douglas acts show that
for every DNA sequence that generates a relatively short functional protein.
There are 10 to the 77th power non functional sequences.
Now consider that there are only 10 to the 65th power atoms in our galaxy.
So finding a new DNA sequence capable of building a functional protein
is like searching blindfolded for a single marked Adam among a trillion Milky Way galaxies
talk about a needle in a haystack
as I show in my book Darwin's doubt,
even four billion years of life's history is not enough time
to overcome a search problem this big
so to Serious doubts about modern darwinian.
The Cambrian explosion the sudden appearance of new animals
which evolutionary theory has failed to explain
and the DNA Enigma the impossibility of random mutations
producing the information needed to build new forms of animal life
scientists who know about these problems are not ignorant stupid or insane.
They are just appropriately skeptical.
I'm Steven Mayer senior fellow at The Discovery Institute for Prager University.
Thank you for watching this video to help keep Prager you videos free.
Please consider making a tax-deductible donation.