I got my PhD in
the field of organic chemistry postdoc at Stanford University joined the group of a man
who is going to win a Nobel Prize in chemistry
voted one of the top 50 most influential Minds in the world.
I was a visiting scholar at Harvard University.
I've spoken it
every major university in this country have over 650 research Publications voted the
Rd magazine scientist of the year.
I'm in the National
enemy of inventors.
I'm a member of the American Association for the advancement of science over a hundred and
twenty patents started
seven or eight companies.
We work in areas that
range from medicine
to Material Science to electronics computer memory medical devices.
We work across a broad range of areas,
but more than any effect.
What means the most to me is that
I'm a Jew who believes that
Jesus is the Messiah
I grew up just outside of New York City.
I thought everybody was Jewish.
I didn't even know that there was
anything else I had no particular interest in that
other than when all my friends were getting bar mitzvahed or
bat mitzvah and
then I would attend of course every week there was never really any excitement for me.
Remember once I even tried to talk to a rabbi.
He just brushed me off.
It was very little explanation for me.
I remember
when I went to college
I started meeting
a number of people that said that they were born again Christians,
which was sort of an odd term.
I was
what born again.
What do you mean born again?
One person saw me in the laundry room if he said
do you mind if I give you an illustration
of the gospel?
And I remember we sat there and
he actually started to draw a picture a cliff with a
With a man on one side and
he drew a little man and
then another Cliff with God on the other side
and a big chasm in between that he labeled.
It's in and looked at him I said,
I'm not a sinner.
I've never killed anyone.
I never robbed the bank.
How could I be a sinner
and he had me read a verse from the Bible
for all have sinned and
fall short of the glory of God
in modern Judaism.
We never really talked about Sin.
I don't remember ever talking about
In in my home,
so he turned to another passage.
Jesus said I say to you that
everyone who looks upon a woman
with Lust For Her
has already committed adultery with her in his heart.
Pop I felt
just
as if I'd been punched right in the chest pure.
I was new in college.
I didn't think anybody knew
I would pick up these magazines and
I became addicted to pornography
who's just through those magazines
and all of a sudden
something that's
written in the Bible.
Somebody from lived who lived 2000 years ago is calling me out on it.
And I felt immediately convicted and
that now I realized I was a sinner.
When I read
in the scriptures,
what sin is
then? I knew I was a sinner.
How am I going to get to God?
We Jews know this better than anyone else without the shedding of blood.
There is no forgiveness of sin
this description in Isaiah 53 of how he will bear
upon himself mice in
the things that I had done.
And this was him.
This was the man
Took this upon himself on the cross.
The perfect God comes and
gives himself for us.
He is the one
that gives himself for us
started to realize
how Jewish
the New Testament is.
This book is so Jewish.
The New Testament is so Jewish.
It's all around Jewish people
and then
on November 7 1977.
I was all alone in my room the realization.
That Yeshua
is the one who died on the cross and
I said Lord,
I am a sinner.
Please forgive me come into my life
and then all of a sudden someone was in my room.
And I opened my eyes.
I was on my knees.
I opened my eyes.
I was in my room that man
Jesus Christ stood in my room.
This amazing sense of God.
Jesus was in my room and
I wasn't scared.
All I started doing was just weeping.
The presence was So Glorious because
he was there in my room on that day.
And I didn't want to get up and
this amazing sense of forgiveness just started to come upon me.
There was a
family I got up.
I didn't know what to do.
I didn't know who to tell yours is Jewish kid from New York City,
but I'm going to say
my cousins were shocked.
How could you do that? You're Jewish telling
my mother how I had invited Jesus into my life.
She didn't say much.
She was weeping.
She told my father they weren't happy at all.
And she said I don't blame them for Killing Jesus after the things that he said,
who is he to come against these religious leaders?
That have dedicated their lives to helping people
and to tell them that
there are whitewashed tombs.
Who is he this young man in his 30s to say this to these Scholars?
He got what he deserved and
my mother's a very deep pensive careful reader.
She read from Genesis right on through the Tanakh the whole thing when she got done.
I said,
what did you think? She said God warned us over and over again?
He warned us when my daughter was about 15 my mother and
father came to visit us.
At one point,
my mother went into her room for several hours.
She came out.
She said the quite a young girl you have she talked to me for a long time.
She started reading the Bible again both the Old and
the New Testament
one day not long after that.
She called me on the phone at the age of 72.
She said Jimmy you wouldn't believe what happened.
This is what happened.
She said I was just reading and
it hit me.
It hit me the way he gave his life.
I believe it now Jesus is the son of God.